Riya KUMARI

HR Aspirants

Address Gurgaon, India 1220124 LinkedIn

Phone +91-9110026627 https://www.linkedin.com/in/riya-

E-mail kumari.riya99rk@gmail.com kumari-326205237/



HR Recruiter in IJRDO JOURNAL School Administrator with more than 1 years of working experience into management. Problem-solving abilities. Roles and responsibilities Current role: Filling positions within an organization. Designing and implementing recruiting systems for the organization. Developing own network of suitable candidates. Handling of administration and record-keeping. Working with organizations to develop a recruitment plan. Executing recruitment plans efficiently. Drafting and posting job descriptions. Interviewing candidates. Preparing job offers. Networking with various institutions and social media. Additional skill sets Records keeping: Keeping records of all the interviews conducted in soft as well as hard copy. Preparation of Offer Letter, Appointment Letter of the selected candidates Conducting various cultural programmers from time to time. Managing Job Portal.

Work History

2022-01 - Current HR Executive

IJRDO JOURNAL, Gurgaon

- · Design and update job descriptions
- · Source potential candidates from various online channels
- Screen incoming resumes and application forms
- Interview candidates (via phone, video and in-person)
- · Provide shortlists of qualified candidates to hiring managers
- Send job offer emails and answer queries about compensation and benefits
- · Participate in job fairs and host in-house recruitment events
- Collaborate with managers to identify future hiring needs
- · Advertise job openings on company's careers page, social media, job boards etc
- Working Into Day To Day Operations.
- Researched and analyzed human resources trends and best practices and drove corporate policy changes to optimize business performance
- · Educated employees on company policy and kept employee handbook current

2022-06 - 2022-08

HR

MAGADH MILK UNION, Bihar

- Learn about the HR tools and the HR policies of the company
- Built human resource organization and aligned people and culture with corporate strategic priorities and operations
- Maintained human resources regulatory compliance with local, state and federal laws
- · Met with employees annually for progress reviews and performance assessments

• Maintained optimal staffing levels by tracking vacancies and initiating recruitment and interview processes to identify qualified candidates

2017-07 - 2020-10 Administrator Cum Teaching

CHILD CARE PUBLIC SCHOOL, Bihar

- Coordinate various faculty searches and maintain faculty search database
- Provide guidance to students on academic goals and educational issues
- · Assist students on course selection, study habits and career selection
- Prepare and maintain student records according to district policies and administrative regulations
- Work with parents, teachers and counselors to address students' behavioral, academic, and other problems
- Coordinate with teachers and center coordinators to develop lesson plans and materials.

Skills

Data analytics.	● ● ● ● ■ ■ Intermediate
Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets.	● ● ● ● Upper intermediate
Microsoft Power point.	● ● ● ● Upper intermediate
MS Word.	● ● ● ● Upper intermediate
Leadership experience.	Advanced
Communication skills.	Advanced
Organizational know-how.	● ● ● ● ● Advanced
People skills.	●●●● Advanced
HRIS Management System	● ● ● ● ● ■ Intermediate
People Management	●●●● Advanced
Recruitment	● ● ● ● ● Advanced
HR support	●●●● Upper intermediate
HR understanding	●●●● Upper intermediate
HR management	●●●● Upper intermediate

Education

2021-01 - Current Masters in Business Administration: Human Resources

Management

Central University Of Jammu - Jammu And Kashmir, India

Talent Acquisition, Research Methodology, Quantitively Technique,

2017-01 - 2020-04 **Bachelors: Commerce**

Gaya College - Bihar, India

Grade: 73.32

Languages

English

Hindi

Advanced

Advanced

Certifications

2023-03 HR data Analytics

2023-04 Certified NPTEL In Sales And Distribution Management

Hobbies

- Painting
- Badminton
- Traveling
- · Cooking